<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="_namespacegame_1_1data_1_1structures" xml:lang="en-US">
<title>game.data.structures Namespace Reference</title>
<indexterm><primary>game.data.structures</primary></indexterm>
<simplesect>
    <title>Namespaces    </title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>namespace <link linkend="_namespacegame_1_1data_1_1structures_1_1map__structure">map_structure</link></para>
</listitem>
            <listitem><para>namespace <link linkend="_namespacegame_1_1data_1_1structures_1_1player__structure">player_structure</link></para>
</listitem>
            <listitem><para>namespace <link linkend="_namespacegame_1_1data_1_1structures_1_1tile__structure">tile_structure</link></para>
</listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
</simplesect>
<section>
<title>Detailed Description</title>

<para><literallayout><computeroutput>Structures are classes containing constants of size, position and other properties of different attributes of an object.
They are used to build compressed packets that aim to be sent to and from the server.

TYPES OF SIZE CONSTANTS:

    - BIT_SIZE
        The bit size constant represents the size of a specific object attribute in bits.
        This means dividing the value by 8 is necessary to obtain a size in bytes.
    - BYTE_SIZE
        The byte size constant represents, as its name suggests, the size of a specific attribute in bytes.

    The reason to having different types of sizes is based on how the &quot;compact packets&quot; are created.
    If they are created specifically utilising bit manipulation operators (&lt;&lt;, &gt;&gt;, &amp;, |, ~, etc.), then bit size
    constants are required, as they are very precise.
    If they are created from direct int to byte conversion (using int.to_bytes() and int.from_bytes()), then the
    precision of the sizes become less important. Direct int - byte conversions are usually done on attributes that
    require more allocated memory and where precision becomes too tedious.

POSITION CONSTANTS:

    The position constants are used to determine where the attributes will be located at in the &quot;compact packet&quot;.
    This is only used for packets that require precise bit manipulation in order to build.

STRUCTURES:

    - PLAYER STRUCTURE
        This contains all constants for player-related packets.
    - MAP STRUCTURE
        This contains all constants for map-related packets.
    - TILE STRUCTURE
        This contains all constants for tile-related packets.
</computeroutput></literallayout> </para>
</section>
</section>
